philipjonlewis@gmail.com +63 916 443 2043 philipjonlewis.com

Philip Jon Echavez Lewis UAP, PIA

Duly Registered & Licensed Architect, Republic of the Philippines Professional Regulatory Commission License Number: 00383344

Skills

Project Management

- Asana
- Notion
- Slack
- Google Producet Suite
- Microsoft Product Suite

Google Product Suite

- Sheets
- Docs
- Slides

Microsoft Product Suite

- Excel
- Word
- Powerpoint

Adobe Suite

- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- InDesign

Front-End

- HTML5
- · CSS + SCSS
- Tailwind
- Typescript + Javascript
- ReactJS + NextJS

Back-End

- NodeJS
- ExpressJS
- REST/RESTful API's

Database

- NoSQL MongoDB
- Redis
- GraphQL
- SQL PostgreSQL

Bundlers & Compilers

- Webpack
- Vite
- Parcel

Other Tech

- Firebase
- Supabase
- Redux
- Redux Toolkit
- RTK Query

UX & UI

- Figma
- AdobeXD

Architecture & 3D

- AutoCAD
- Sketchup
- VrayLumion
- Lamon

Version Control

- Git
- GitHub

GitHub Account

github.com/philipjonlewis

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/philipjonlewis

Professional Summary

Aspiring business, development & project professional as well as a highly motivated **architect**, **designer & software engineer** with 6+ years experience in the AEC industry as a practicing architect and 2+ years experience building a one man startup.

Self-directed startup founder, UX/UI designer & software engineer. Developed and built bespoke software for the AEC industry from scratch.

In previous positions held, managed the design and production of multiple architectural projects while simultaneously handling contract negotiations, client presentations and technical coordination with engineers, suppliers & other allied professionals in the construction industry.

Highly productive in challenging environments that are open to a multi-disciplinary approach to progress.

Keen on growing as a technically competent leader, a flexible team-player, and a productive member of the organization.

Work Experience

Owner & Software Engineer

WestXDX - Sole Proprietor

2020 - 2022

- Owner & Full Stack Developer of WestXDX, a one man startup currently working on bespoke software for the AEC (Architecture, Engineering & Construction) Industry. Current projects include the ff:
 - TapTapTask (taptaptask.com) a task-management tool for phase-based projects. front end code made with Vite, ReactJS, Redux Toolkit, RTK Query, CSS + SASS and backend code made with NodeJS+Express & MongoDB. All written in typescript. (full code on my github profile)
 - QuickNotes (quicknotesbyphilip.netlify.app) a minimalist block style editor made with typescript, google firebase for the database, React, Vite, EditorJS, CSS + SASS.
 - Archestimator (archestimator.com) currently an ongoing project. a construction cost estimator for architects. Currently building with typescript, svelte, vite + rollup & supabase. Exploring moving to sveltekit once the framework becomes more stable.

Owner & Principal Architect

Architect Philip Jon E. Lewis - Private Practice

2016 - 2022

- · Owner & Principal Architect of Ar. Philip Jon E. Lewis, an architectural design practice.
 - The practice handled multiple architectural & interior projects but mainly consist of the commercial, office, & residential type. Handled 2-4 contract staff at any given time.
 - Responsibilities mainly compose of project management, client management, contract negotiations, design proposal presentations and leading the design and architectural project management of the production of design and contract documents needed for building permits & actual physical construction.
 - Coordinated with multiple third party suppliers, engineers, mall administration and other allied fields with regards to the design, construction & completion of multiple projects.
 - · Scope of responsibility include, but are not limited to the following:
 - Project Management
 - Client Relationship ManagementContract Negotiations
 - Architectural Practice ManagementArchitectural Design, Planning & Interiors
 - Technical Coordinations
 - Design Proposal Presentations
 - · Supplier, Contractor & Engineering Coordination
 - Computer Aided Design & Construction Blueprints
 - Detailed Contract Documentation

philipjonlewis@gmail.com +63 916 443 2043 philipjonlewis.com

Philip Jon Echavez Lewis UAP, PIA

Duly Registered & Licensed Architect, Republic of the Philippines Professional Regulatory Commission License Number: 00383344

Educational Background

Bachelor of Science in Architecture

The Pontifical & Royal University of Santo Tomas

2009 - 2015

- · Graduated with an Outstanding Thesis Award.
- Involved with various student organizations such as UAPSA-UST, Architect, Student Council & The Heritage Conservation Society.

High School Diploma

Elizabeth Seton School - Main Campus, Las Pinas City

2005 - 2009

Additional Work Experience

Assistant Architect & Planner

Architect Chona Elvas-Ponce, UAP

2015

- Created design, marketing & visualization materials in order to communicate the plan & vision of various projects and ssisted the principal architect in the planning & design of various masterplanned projects.
- Provided presentation drawings and renderings for a small scaled residential community that helped in client & project acquisition & completion.

Assistant Architect

Architect Charisse Ong, UAP

2014

- Assisted the principal architect in the 2D Encoding & 3D Modelling of various residential condominium fit out projects.
- Aided in the detection of clashes and errors in architectural & engineering drawings & documents.
- Built a strong relationship with the principal architect wherein she turned out to by one of my closest mentors and confidants up to the present.

Professional Certificates & Online Courses

Google

Through Coursera

- · Google Project Management
- Google UX Design

California Intitute of the Arts

Through Coursera

- UI / UX Design
- Graphic Design

UC Irvine

Through Coursera

· Project Management Principles & Practice

THe Hong Kong University of Science & Technology

Through Coursera

· Full Stack Web Development with React

Zero-To-Mastery Academy

Through Udemy

- · Complete Python Developer
- The Complete Web Developer
- JavaScript : The Advanced Concepts
- Complete Guide to Freelancing
- Complete Web & Mobile Designer: UI/UX & Figma.

Academind

Through Udemy

- MongoDB The Complete Developers Guide
- NodeJs The Complete Guide (MVC, REST API's, GraphQL, Deno)
- CSS The Complete Guide

philipjonlewis@gmail.com +63 916 443 2043 philipjonlewis.com

Philip Jon Echavez Lewis UAP, PIA

Duly Registered & Licensed Architect, Republic of the Philippines Professional Regulatory Commission License Number: 00383344

Publications Appeared/Featured In

Shelter Magazine

Architecture Dichotomies

· Article: The Finer Class - A Continued Search for Architecture's Rising Vanguards

Awards & Recognitions

Outstanding Thesis Award

University Of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture

Seminars / Workshops Spoken At

Archive - Powered By Pecha Kucha

University of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture

UST Archinet - Architecture Network

Mulayin - Photoshop + Visualization & Post Processing Workshop

University of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture

UST College of Architecture Student Council

Ukit - Tracing Our Roots Through Philippine Architecture

University of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture

United Architects of the Philippines - Student Auxiliary UST Chapter

Ideate - Architecture Thesis Forum

University of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture

UST Scarlet Architecture & UST College of Architecture Student Council

Trivium - Business in Architecture

University of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture

UST Archinet - Architecture Network

Professional Development & Associated Experiences

Advisory Board Member

United Architects of the Philippines - Student Auxiliary UST Chapter

2014, 2016

Chapter President

United Architects of the Philippines - Graduate Auxiliary Manila Chapter

2015

Creative Director

University of Santo Tomas - College of Architecture Student Council

2013

Creative Director

19th UAPSA National Congress - United Architects of the Philippines - Student Auxiliary UST Chapter

2013

Philippine Delegate

4th Malaysian International Youth Programme

2012

Technical Director

UST Archinet - Architecture Network

2012

Chief-Of-Staff

United Architects of the Philippines - Student Auxiliary UST Chapter

philipjonlewis@gmail.com +63 916 443 2043 philipjonlewis.com

Philip Jon Echavez Lewis UAR, PIA

Duly Registered & Licensed Architect, Republic of the Philippines Professional Regulatory Commission License Number: 00383344

Other Professional Certificates & Courses

Master Digital Product Design: UX Research & UI Design

• Rob Sutcliffe - Udemy

The Strategy of Content Marketing

· University of California, Davis: Through Coursera

Business Writing

· University of Colorado, Boulder: Through Coursera

Graphic Design

· University of Colorado, Boulder: Through Coursera

Introduction to UI Design

· University of Minnesota: Through Coursera

Responsive Website Basics: Code with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

· University of London: Through Coursera

Transacting on the BlockChain

· Insead: Through Coursera

Introduction to Blockchain Technologies

· Insead: Through Coursera

Digital Marketing

HubSpot Academy

The Branding Masterclass - The Entire Brand Design Process

• Linday Marsh - Udemy

Design Thinking & Global Startup

• Korean Advanced Institute of Sciente & Technology : Through Coursera

The Complete Copywriting Course - Write to Sell Like a Pro

• Tamsin Henderson - Udemy

Build a lucrative Copywriting Portfolio with Ease

• Tamsin Henderson - Udemy

Digital Skills: User Experience

FutureLearn

Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner

• IBM

The Modern Javascript Bootcamp

• Andrew Mead - Udemy

Introduction to Corporate Finance

• Wharton Online : Through Coursera

Introduction to Financial Accounting

• Wharton Online : Through Coursera

Introduction to Marketing

• Wharton Online: Through Coursera

Managing Social and Human Capital

• Wharton Online : Through Coursera